<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events - Collection | ProxyGeek Blog</title><link>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/collections/events/</link><description>Author of Hugo FixIt, fond of experimenting, building tools, and writing. Sharing thoughts, experiences, and observations in front-end development.</description><generator>Hugo 0.153.4 &amp; FixIt v0.4.0-alpha.2</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</managingEditor><webMaster>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 05:24:44 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/collections/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LeHack Adventure 2025</title><link>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/hack5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 10:47:00 +0200</pubDate><author>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</author><guid>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/hack5/</guid><category domain="https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/categories/thoughts/">Thoughts</category><description>&lt;p&gt;LeHack, one of the most renowned cybersecurity events in Europe, had been on my radar for a while. Known for its thrilling Capture The Flag (CTF) challenges, hands-on workshops, and the opportunity to meet some of the brightest minds in cybersecurity, I knew it would be a day to remember. From the moment I registered, I couldn’t wait to dive into the challenges that awaited me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving, the buzz was palpable. People from all walks of cybersecurity—ethical hackers, penetration testers, and curious enthusiasts—gathered under one roof to push the limits of what we could learn and achieve. The event had a relaxed yet competitive vibe, and I was immediately pulled into the spirit of the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshops were a perfect mix of theory and practice. One of the most interesting sessions was dedicated to &lt;strong&gt;IoT vulnerabilities&lt;/strong&gt;. We learned how easily common devices could be exploited if not properly secured. It was fascinating to see the instructor demonstrate in real time how an insecure device could be hacked—something I had only read about until then. The hands-on nature of these sessions made it feel less like a lecture and more like an immersion into real-world hacking.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>