<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome - Collection | ProxyGeek Blog</title><link>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/collections/welcome/</link><description>Author of Hugo FixIt, fond of experimenting, building tools, and writing. Sharing thoughts, experiences, and observations in front-end development.</description><generator>Hugo 0.147.9 &amp; FixIt v0.3.21-b2e6f70a</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</managingEditor><webMaster>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 23:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/collections/welcome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Github Workflow</title><link>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/github/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 18:26:49 +0200</pubDate><author>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</author><guid>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/github/</guid><category domain="https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/categories/thoughts/">Thoughts</category><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Behind every well-organized repo lies a story of purpose, experimentation, and constant iteration.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 class="heading-element" id="about">&lt;span>13 About&lt;/span>
 &lt;a href="#about" class="heading-mark">
 &lt;svg class="octicon octicon-link" viewBox="0 0 16 16" version="1.1" width="16" height="16" aria-hidden="true">&lt;path d="m7.775 3.275 1.25-1.25a3.5 3.5 0 1 1 4.95 4.95l-2.5 2.5a3.5 3.5 0 0 1-4.95 0 .751.751 0 0 1 .018-1.042.751.751 0 0 1 1.042-.018 1.998 1.998 0 0 0 2.83 0l2.5-2.5a2.002 2.002 0 0 0-2.83-2.83l-1.25 1.25a.751.751 0 0 1-1.042-.018.751.751 0 0 1-.018-1.042Zm-4.69 9.64a1.998 1.998 0 0 0 2.83 0l1.25-1.25a.751.751 0 0 1 1.042.018.751.751 0 0 1 .018 1.042l-1.25 1.25a3.5 3.5 0 1 1-4.95-4.95l2.5-2.5a3.5 3.5 0 0 1 4.95 0 .751.751 0 0 1-.018 1.042.751.751 0 0 1-1.042.018 1.998 1.998 0 0 0-2.83 0l-2.5 2.5a1.998 1.998 0 0 0 0 2.83Z">&lt;/path>&lt;/svg>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>&lt;p>After years of hands-on experience in cybersecurity and development, I’ve learned that code is just one part of the battle. The &lt;strong>structure&lt;/strong> we build around our work — our process, our repository, our mindset — is what allows our projects to scale, evolve, and remain resilient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 02:47:00 +0200</pubDate><author>1024@Pr0xyG33k.github.io (ProxyGeek)</author><guid>https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><category domain="https://Pr0xyG33k.github.io/categories/thoughts/">Thoughts</category><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What wakes you up every morning is not the alarm clock, but your dreams.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I’ve lived through moments where this belief kept me going. I’ve seen the effort I’ve put into my work, and now, as I look back, the real question isn’t whether I’ve earned what I have — it’s about continuing to push forward, unflinching in the face of challenges.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In cybersecurity, the fight is never over. It’s a world where the enemy never sleeps, and neither should we.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my early days in tech, grappling with complex algorithms and shifting to cybersecurity, the road has been long. I started with basic coding, moved to penetration testing, then switched to defensive security, teaching interns, and tackling real-world security problems. Every step has been driven by &lt;strong>curiosity&lt;/strong> and the desire to &lt;strong>defend&lt;/strong> what matters — our digital lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time doesn’t pause because we hesitate. Like you, there are countless others chasing their dreams. No one is born a cybersecurity expert, but each day is an opportunity to grow, to protect, and to evolve. Never be content with where you are; always strive to learn, to adapt, and to secure.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>